hey what's up everybody anthony sevens
back again for another product review
and today we're going to be talking
about arcade one ups 2021 countercame
nba jam let's rock and roll
[Music]
so before we even open this bad boy up
and start digging around with it let's
talk about this packaging for a minute
holy [\h__\h]
i mean
a little handle and everything
arcade one up is getting fancy on us in
2021 this year
spin it to the side
take a look wow
i'm uh
you know i had my doubts and gripes
about these new uh
countercades
but uh
i can clearly say i'm a bit impressed
all right let's uh let's plug this guy
in and see what he can do
one thing i wanted to show that i really
like is that when it comes to the film
that you have to peel off i like how
they've already got it started for you
so you're not sitting there scratching
at anything and taking a chance
scratching up your machine so that's a
pretty cool little little [\h__\h] number
one
so nba jam the original arcade game came
out in 1993 just one short year after
the release of the original mortal
kombat arcade and the same exact year
that mortal kombat part 2 the arcade
game was released so imagine living in a
time where you first get mortal kombat 2
and this cool ass basketball game called
nba jam all in the same year arcades
were booming in the early 1990s i'll
tell you that much but see what's really
special about nba jam to me
is that admittingly so i'm not a sports
person i really don't like sports nor do
i ever fiend to play sports games so
when nba jam came out you know living in
illinois the chicago bulls were
doing spectacular to say the least you
could go look up that information online
about the chicago bulls in the 1990s
anyways something no matter who you were
whether you were a fan of basketball or
not you at least knew what was going on
in the chicagoland area with the chicago
bulls and you know if there was nothing
else on at that time yeah you know
admittingly i wound up watching some
games especially the championship
victories and all that other stuff but
anyway so now this this new basketball
arcade game called nba jam gets released
at the arcades and it really was to me a
non-sports fan like
oh a new basketball game i wonder what
this is about
and
you go and you put in your quarters and
next thing you know you've got three
buttons and a joystick and you are in
control of very famous basketball
players it's a two-on-two basketball
game pretty much um and but what's what
made it really cool and attractive to a
non-sports player like me number one it
was super easy to figure out and play
number two it was super [\h__\h]
addicting because once you got a hang of
the controls
you know
you were just you didn't want to stop
playing but what was really super cool
is that this is like a two on two
basketball game with super powers if you
make three baskets in a row without the
other team scoring your player
catches on fire as they say
he's on fire and the basketball is on
fire and every shot that you make is
like this cool
super powered super shot and you're just
slam dunking this ball left and right
and trying to score some three pointers
for some extra points so it is a really
it is a very unorthodox game of
basketball featuring super powers and it
just was it's really fast paced really
high energy and really fun and what what
added to all of that uh was the
announcer that that in hearing you you
hear things like the announcer screaming
boom shakalaka or he's on fire and and
all these other little
quirky things and it was just a very
energetic arcade game that again was
very attractive to a non-sports player
like me so just like mortal kombat and
mortal kombat 2 of that time i can
clearly admit being a non-sports dude
that i played the ship out of nba jam
when it came to the arcade
so now to see it you know
in a home version a little miniature
arcade um is is
it's cool you know another favorite in
my home and i'm very impressed now i did
have two choices at this point in time
in 2021 there are two versions of nba
jam available to the general public that
arcade one up makes one is a full-size
four-player uh stand-up floor cabinet
and the other is this in 2021 they
decided to come out with the
a a new version of the countercade which
now features a couple of things it now
features two player controls it features
a light up marquee which uh countercase
beforehand didn't offer it's got
gorgeous uh cabinet work uh it's got a
headphone jack
for those who uh
want to have a little more personalized
experience and it has a usb port if you
want to throw in uh and play with a
second player controller if these
controls are too close together to be
comfortable so um
man
color me impressed
you know i had my doubts as i stated
early on i had my doubts about arcade
one ups counter cage because they're
just so small and i didn't think that
you know
previously having owned the original uh
centipede countercade i was a little
kind of okay you know whatever but now
you know you're dealing with a game that
came out in the early 90s so the
graphics got to be on point the gameplay
has got to be on point you know it's not
just some classic arcade with a fire
button or a roller i mean now there's a
little bit more sophisticatedness going
on here plus on this gorgeous gorgeous
screen let's talk about the screen for a
moment if you've seen other reviews
you've heard people talk about the
screen
it is
awesome
for being an 8-inch screen it is awesome
the color the graphics
and i even believe p-dub even stated in
his review that once you're playing for
several minutes you kind of don't even
pay attention that you're playing on an
8-inch screen anymore and that that's
100 true i will vouch for that it's it's
really i'm very impressed by this it
looks great it plays great it's got all
this cool [\h__\h] the one thing too that i
love about the screen that people have
bought up is that no matter what angle
you're looking i'm like on the side of
this machine right now right and i'm
looking at the screen from this angle
and it is not washed out in any way
shape or form i can clearly see the
graphics and what's going on and how
vibrant the screen is even on a slight
angle one of the reasons why they do
this as opposed to the older games is
that because the control deck the
controls are so close together in order
for you to comfortably play with two
players one player's got to be kind of
on a kitty corner and the other player's
got to be on a kitty corner so
the screen needs to adapt to the
different viewing angles for a
comfortability
and i think that that's beautiful just
that you think about how they thought
about something like that like so small
like well there's gonna be two people we
need to fix our screens and put a
monitor in here so i'm super hyper
impressed with everything on this you
know i've already played it for a few
moments uh before i started recording
this video that everything is is great
about it um
so the other thing i can do is just kind
of show you the graphics and everything
oh the speaker the speaker is underneath
the machine so definitely not a machine
that you want to play on top of fabric
such as carpet or bed sheets or you'll
completely muffle the sound
it is not the loudest speaker in the
world but in comparison to previous uh
countercade releases it is it's
definitely louder and i kind of like
that they put it underneath because on a
hard surface the sound kind of splashes
outward and sitting down especially
you get a better sound experience from
it all so anyways
let's get into some gameplay
all right and away we go look at that
even the marquis on this looks
absolutely stunning it's sharp it's
crispy
um definitely um let's see if i can
focus there we go uh definitely a hell
of a lot better than the original light
up marquis they had
years prior
wow
all right
see it's it's a nice nice sound for
being such a little machine very
impressive
all right let's see what we can do here
now um
all right so we got nba jam
nba jam hang time
or nba hang time sorry and then nba jam
tournament edition
so let's start with regular nba jam
wow that is that is one hell of a
picture for a little eight inch screen
welcome to nba gym
welcome indeed
keeping your initials
okay
birthday revealing secrets
so yeah everything looks wow this is
it is it's
it's just as i remember it in the arcade
except in a very micro version
[Music]
i really do wish the sound was slightly
louder but we're just gonna
[\h__\h] around here
[Applause]
[Music]
delivers the facial i love it i love
that guy's voice
[Applause]
awesome all right let's check out the
next
game nba jam tournament edition
[Music]
all right
very
very beautiful i mean it's
i am really beyond
i know i keep saying it impressed
wow okay
the controls are extremely responsive on
this
well
tonight's matchup world's birthday
mavericks
[Applause]
yeah with the three
[Music]
[Applause]
very very cool all right next game
and just like the the newer 2021 games
too
i wanted to show if you push the player
1 and player 2 button at the same time
you go to the pause menu where you can
either resume game reset game or quit
game
and now to nba hang time
time
you know and for it's uh i'm just gonna
put in some stuff
blah blah okay cool cool
[Music]
all right this is robin
the chicago bull versus
well this game had a different voice and
different characters and stuff
cartoony
was more of a cartoony type of announcer
voice
[Applause]
all right let's get out of here
so yeah as far as you know as far as nba
jam is concerned i mean it plays just
like the original arcade i love the
sound i love the graphics on this and uh
you know i definitely take back any kind
of uh seemingly negative any things that
i have ever put towards arcade one ups
countercades specifically
it really is it is fantastic
for small spaces it's fantastic for
travel it's it's got a bit of weight to
it so it's not going to wobble all over
the place although what i plan on doing
is making a game table so i'm going to
use little l brackets to actually secure
and mount this to the table so no matter
you know who's playing no matter how
rough you get with it you know it's not
going to be scooching around anywhere so
that's an idea that you might think
about doing uh but yeah i am just i'm
super beyond
ecstatic about about this machine and
you know for those who collect the
countercades and have not gotten this
yet i think you're going to be pretty
impressed as well it is nba jam still
remains a fun
high intense game
it's fast paced it's easy to learn it's
addictive as hell uh and with what what
arcade one up has done you know just
with with just seeing the two player
controls on here
it's just like damn that's that's
that's super cool and i cannot wait for
them to incorporate something like this
on the on the uh the party cage or the
wall caves because it's it's just it's
very comfortable
i don't feel you know a lot of people
are worried about and all the controls
are too close together for two i don't
think you're gonna have a huge huge
problem with that uh and you have to
keep in mind too most of us gamers who
are building at home arcades we're
playing by ourselves like 98 of the time
so
as one player and a person who's gonna
play this quite frequently by myself uh
the second player controller isn't too
close and won't get in the way and if
they need to be i go from this position
to slide over a little bit and again
just being able to see the screen at an
angle crystal clear
it doesn't bother me at all um
the only gripe that i would say is that
i wish it was louder other than that you
know i'm giving i'm giving the 2021 nba
jam counter kid by arcade one up
two crispy thumbs up
and uh i i can't wait to to get the uh
marvel superheroes one that's gonna be
my next one and possibly my only other
countercade that i currently own
and and will own but uh you know setting
up a little sit-down gaming table i just
thought that the the counter kids were
going to be perfect for that and
i was right that was right so anyways go
get yourself one i think they're
retailing it
a little over 200 it's currently around
the holiday season right now so you can
get them
cheaper
but i think without
the uh without the holiday sales you're
looking you're pushing like 250 or
something like that for the original
price of these
some of you might be saying well
whatever happened at the countercades of
old where they promised us you know it
was going to be
100 bucks for a unit well you know all
things considered you know they have a
brand new updated amazing looking
monitor on these they now have the light
up mark keys they have dual controls
extra [\h__\h] extra money
so
do i believe it's worth that 219 220
price range
and you know the only reason why i argue
against it is because the uh the party
kates were also uh
219 bucks well mine was at least and to
have a unit that was 219 and with a full
17 inch screen and this is an 8 inch
screen i understand you need to up the
price but i think that that 219 that 250
is a little much i would have loved to
see
the counter cade at more like 150 to 175
i believe that that is definitely worth
it
but i am impressed and there's certainly
no regrets
as far as just adding another favorite
game to the arcade that's all i got for
you guys this is anthony seven signing
off until we meet again take care of
yourself take care of each other
[Music]